now in this lesson we're going to focus
on
converting logarithmic expressions
into exponential equations
so consider this logarithmic expression
log base 3 of 9
is equal to 2.
how can you convert it from logarithmic
form to exponential form
well here is the generic equation let's
say if we have log base a
of b is equal to c
a
raised to the c
is equal to b
so this is the equivalent expression in
exponential form
so likewise three
raised to the second power is equal to
nine
so we can write it as three squared
is equal to nine
now it's your turn
convert the following logarithmic
expression
into its exponential form and you can
try this one as well
4 raised to the third power
is equal to 64.
so that's how you can write it in
exponential form
eight raised to the second power is
equal to 64.
and so we can write it like this
now what about the reverse
let's say if we have an equation
in exponential form
convert it to logarithmic form
try these three examples
feel free to pause the video
so the base is two the base is the one
with the exponent
so log base 2
and what is across the equal side
will go here
and
the logarithmic function always equals
the exponent
so to check it you can see that 2 raised
to the third power
is equal to 8.
the next one is going to be log base 4
of 16
is equal to the exponent
which is two
four raised to the second power is equal
to sixteen
for the last one log
base five the base is the one with the
exponent
of 125
is equal to the exponent of three
five
to the third power is equal to 125
you